

# ALEXANDER FERRARA

182 Sixth Street NW, Atlanta, GA 30313 | aferrara3@gatech.edu | 678-749-8826 AlexanderFerrara.com

## **OBJECTIVE**

I seek an internship or co-op position to further extend my range of skills and to gain more experience working in a professional environment in a field relevant to my studies. Some level of hardware development exposure is preferred but not required.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY**

Atlanta, GA

School of Electrical and Computer Engineering

August 2013 – May 2017

81 credit hours completed

3.50 Cumulative GPA

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Booz | Allen | Hamilton** 

Atlanta, GA

Full-time during summer semesters, half-time throughout main academic semesters

May 2014 – Present

#### **Developer Intern**

- Contracted with the Center for Disease Control and Prevention, working directly on client projects.
- Developed skills with numerous new programming languages and vastly expanded my skillset.
- Worked on a project team utilizing the agile methodology.
- Gained experience working on a project through various stages of a software performance lifecycle (EPLC).
- Contributed source code directly to multiple web application projects for client.

Gasthaus Tirol Cumming, GA

Received training and 18 months of experience

May 2012 – August 2013

## Sous Chef

- Trained kitchen staff including replacement dish washer and sous chefs, emphasizing efficiency.
- Developed leadership in a high-pressure food service environment.
- Acquired excellent skills in multi-tasking and time management.
- Obtained exposure to working with individuals of various cultural backgrounds.

Dish Washer March 2012 – May 2012

Maintained sanitary requirements of the restaurant

#### SKILLS AND INTERESTS

**Proficiencies:** C++, Digital Logic Design, MIPS Assembly, Java, JavaScript, C, jQuery, HTML, CSS3

**Experience with:** MATLAB, VHDL, Signal Processing, C#, SQL, ASP .NET, Python **Personal Skills:** Leadership, Organizational, Multi-tasking, Adaptable, Fast Learner

**Volunteer:** Atlanta Mission, Seven Bridges, Dodging Domestic Violence

**Awards Received:** Eagle Scout, Zell Miller Scholarship Recipient *August 2013 – Present,* International AP Scholar

**Affiliations:** Kappa Sigma Fraternity, Wreck Racing automotive club

Last updated: 2015-07-25